A Guide to the Papers of Stephen Davidson Tuttle,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Stephen Davidson Tuttle
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3990, 3990-a, 3990-b
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 3990 was a gift of Stephen Tuttle, 1952 September 1. Accession 3990-a was a gift of Ernest Mead, 1964 June 26. Accession 3990-b was an archival transfer from the Music Library, 1989 October 18.
Scope and Content
The papers concern Tuttle's activities as a member of the Music Dept. at the University of Virginia, including correspondence, programs and photographs pertaining to the Virginia Celebrity Concerts, 1945-1950, which featured Zino Francescatti, Robert Casadesus, Helen Traubel, the Robert Shaw Chorale and the Philadelphia Orchestra.
The collection also contain thirty musical scores arranged by Tuttle for a proposed book by Helen Bullock on Jefferson and music; correspondence with Archibald T. Davison and William Weedon relating to the 1950 Page Barbour Lecture; a manuscript compositon A Carol for Christmas; and letters from E. H. Fellowes, Hans Kindler, Karl Kreuger, Jan LaRue, Denis Stevens and John Cook Wyllie.
The collection also contains a printed program for the concert in dedication of the Stephen Davidson Tuttle Memorial Harpsichord, signed by Randall Thompson and others; a copy of Tuttle's dissertation on William Byrd, an illustrated concert program for La Serenade with cover sketch by Christian Bêrard; and some Chinese chops.
Contents List
- A Carol for Christmas Eve by Stephen Davidson Tuttle, n. d. (Box 1)
- Illustrated Concert Program for La Serenade with cover sketch by Christian Bêrard, 1933, Drawing scanned as prints05700, original in boxed UVA Visual History RG-30/1/10.011.
- Letters to Stephen Davidson Tuttle and Lucile Tuttle from E. H. Fellowes, Jan LaRue, John Cook Wyllie, and Denis Stevens, 1949-1957 (Box 2)
- Material for proposed book by Helen Bullock on Jefferson and Music, n. d. (Box 3)
- Page-Barbour Lectures: Correspondence, including letters from Archibald T. Davison of Harvard University and William S. Weedon, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
- Photographs of Zino Francescatti, Robert Shaw, Robert Shaw Chorale, and Helen Traubel, n. d. (Box 5)
- Photographs of the McIntire Department of Music, 1943, n.d. (Box 6)
- Printed Material re: Stephen Davidson Tuttle, and related- reviews, program Dedication of The Stephen Davidson Tuttle Memorial Harpsichord,1951-1963 (Box 7)
- Virginia Celebrity Concerts: Correspondence concerning the upcoming concerts of Zino Francescatti, Eugene Ormandy and the Philadelphia Symphony Orchestra, the Robert Shaw Chorale, Robert Casadesus, and Helen Traubel, 1947-1951 (Box 8)
- Virginia Celebrity Concerts: Programs, Ticket Receipts and Sales, etc., 1949-1950 (Box 9)
- William Byrd A Study of the History of English Keyboard Music to 1623, a thesis by Stephen Davidson Tuttle, n.d., 1 of 2 folders. (Box 10)
- William Byrd A Study of the History of English Keyboard Music to 1623, a thesis by Stephen Davidson Tuttle, n.d. (Box 11)
  2 of 2 folders.